Hello everyone. Welcome back to our SQL TUTIO series. So today we are going to delve into the
logical operators for and or and the not in the SQL and these are incredibly useful for creating
the complex conditions in our queries, okay. So first of all here I can define for the SQL logical
operator, okay. So the logical operator for and or not allow a combined condition in the SQL
queries and providing for the flexibility and the precision in the data you tried. So let's
explore for how to use this work with some example, okay. So first of all here we can use the
and operator, okay. So now let's start and allow the specified multiple condition that must be
so all the two are in the report to be included in the results set, okay. So I can just do it
with tubing or it is we need two specific columns, okay. So first of all here we can type create the
image and type this is the select the next form the employee stable and next step here I can use the
where department. So this is the department column and we're going to insert for the department of
IT, okay. And here I can apply for the end of it and create another column for these greater than
30, okay. So define perfectly and here selecting the report from the employee stable and where the
department for the IT and the age is greater than 30 and now I can select this data query and execute
now you can see here the employee only for the column and now just go for here column with the row,
okay. Now here change for is define for the 29, okay. Now just again select an execute and you can
see here this output for the employee on then zoom in and here is the 30 and the department
for IT, okay. So this department and older is 30. So complete an assistant create a, use the
auto priority, okay. So now just use the auto priority and first of all here create the department
for the ID, the IT department and just apply for here the auto priority and again again use the
department. So define for here the department column and it's equal to here I can just type for the
HR department, okay. So here select the report from the employee stable and when the department is
either IT or HR and here just select an execute now you can see here only for here you can see the
IT department, okay. So here I can just change so inside the marketing. So now here going to the
marketing department and then just again select an execute and you can see here the perfect
separated for because you're already created for the department information for the IT department
and also put in for here the marketing department, okay. So this is the complete to example and
here create using the auto priority, okay. So the auto priority is negative under condition
returning records that do not make the space be conditioned, okay. So now just go here and first of all
here I'll be it and select start from the employee stable and where you're supposed like
not the department for only use the IT department, okay. So now just remove this data query and here
in the example just select the records from the input table where the department is not
in the IT department, okay. Now just select an execute and as you can see the result. So you can see
here the step is not department for the IT and this query will return to ISO do not work in the
IT department, okay. So you can check here the procedure department, the civil marketing
finance and about we are not sure the IT department, okay. So understanding and also here
create for the combining the logical operators, okay. So you can combine the angle and not
create complex condition, okay. So first of all just go again here and then remember it is not
a priority and first of all I'll create suppose like create the parentheses is equal to IT department,
okay. And I will apply for the end of the total. So here the age is greater than 29, okay.
And create complete the parentheses and here I can use the another department. So now just
define for the department is equal to create for a software, okay. So this is completely defined and
selecting the request for the employee stable the department the IT and age is greater than 29
or the department is the software and here first of all I can select only for select and
then execute and now you can see here the step for the department for the IT here is the age for 30
okay. And here just change so here inside for the age is 25 and then again select now execute and
you can see here point we state the IT department. So in this data is usually an employee who had
either the older than 20 to 30 and works live department and work in the software department,
okay. So there we have it and what we have the logical operators and the SQL for some practical
example, okay. So I hope you guys will understand this session. So thank you for watching and happy
coding.